businesspatrol.com 2011-01-29

# International Business Leads, Business List, Business Information, International Trade, Business Search, International Business Directory, Marketing and Business Opportunities

We have developed this policy as part of our commitment to protecting your privacy, while providing a valuable and personalised service. We want you to feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information. This policy applies whether or not you choose to register for Businesspatrol.com services.   
We collect personal information about you when you register with Businesspatrol.com and if you buy advertising products as a business.   
When you register with Businesspatrol.com we ask you for details about yourself because we want to ensure that we give you a service that's tailored for you. We ask for as little information as possible in order to make it a quick and easy process. The information you give us isn't sold on to other companies and we have a serious and dedicated commitment to the security of your information. 

**Collected information**

 _What information do I give you as a user of Businesspatrol.com?_   
Registration into the "Trade Desk"   
If you register with us, we ask you for a small amount of information. We do this so that when you return to Businesspatrol.com, we can instantly recognise you and give you access to your address book. Details we collect may include:   

-Company Name   
-Last Name   
-Email adress   
-Gender   
-Position into the company   
-Country of origin of the company   
-Activity sector of the company   
-Web site URL of the company
  
During your session as a registered user we use a cookie to store an encoded version of your Businesspatrol.com user ID so that you can access your address book. If you have cookies disabled on your browser you will not be able to use log in as a registered user. _What information do I give you as a customer/advertiser of Businesspatrol.com?_   
1- Registration:   
Registering your company details enables us to give you private access to details we might be holding for you, like account information. We only collect the minimum information required to identify you and to ensure that we provide you with appropriate information. Details we collect may include:   

-forename and surname;   
-company name;   
-company address;   
-telephone number;   
-e-mail address.
  
2- Orders:   
When you order an advertisement or domain name on Businesspatrol.com we need to know a little bit about you. This enables us to process and fulfil your order, or contact you in case of a query. Details we may collect include:   

-forename and surname;   
-company name;   
-position;   
-company address;   
-telephone number;   
-e-mail address.
  
_Why do you need my e-mail address?_   
We need your e-mail address to give you security. As a registered user, you have to enter a password to access your Businesspatrol.com Trade Desk area-no one else can access it-and if you forget your password, we can e-mail it to you. We also use your e-mail address to confirm your order details to you.   
We might also use the information you've given us to bring you important news such as functionality changes to the Businesspatrol.com site or new services and special offers you might find valuable. This is only sent to users who have chosen to opt in when registering, and each time we e-mail you, you can choose not to be sent any further messages from us. We'll also guarantee not to "spam" you with annoying, irrelevant e-mails. 

**Stored information**

 _Do you store information on my browsing activity, and can I be identified from it?_   
During your search session on Businesspatrol.com we will store the location you have requested. This is to enable you to search other types of business without having to re-enter the location every time. This information is only retained while you are searching and will not be kept once you have left Businesspatrol.com. We also collect anonymous information on your activity while logged into Businesspatrol.com such as:   

-IP address;   
-browser type;   
-access times;   
-referring URL.
  
There's no way you can be identified as a result of your browsing activity on Businesspatrol.com.   
We only examine browsing activity to monitor aggregated site traffic and analyse it. This gives us information to help us improve the relevance of the services we offer you.   
We may also provide anonymous statistics about users to reputable third party vendors, but these will not include details that would allow the recipient to identify you. _As an advertiser, do you store information on me?_   
Yes, but we only store information that we need to operate effectively, and it is stored securely in our main database. 

**How we use cookies**

 _What is a cookie?_   
A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are.   
A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. Two types of cookies are used on this website-session cookies, which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site, and persistent cookies, which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie).   
Cookies can help a website to arrange content to match your preferred interests more quickly. Most major websites use cookies. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you. _How do you use cookies and what information do you collect about me?_   
Session cookies   
We use temporary/session cookies in the following ways:   
within Businesspatrol.com search to identify the registrant   
If you don't want a cookie to be created on your PC, you will be not able to access to the Trade Desk area.   
Once the session if finished ( you click on the sign-out button or you close the Internet Explorer software) the cookie will be destroyed on your PC.   
[Find out more about how to disable cookies](http://www.yell.com/legal/cookies/home.html#10).   
Sites linked to Businesspatrol.com may also use cookies. Please check the individual privacy policies of such sites to find out more. _What is a web beacon?_   
A web beacon-sometimes referred to as a clear GIF (Graphics Interchange Format) or pixel tag-is a line of code that we have installed on some of our pages to help us learn more about how our visitors interact with the content and services that we offer, and to count the traffic to different areas of the website. A web beacon is a 1x1 pixel tag that is invisible to you and doesn't affect the content you see.   
This helps us provide a better service to you by allowing us to understand which areas of the site are more popular with visitors than others. Web beacons are not used to collect any personal information about you. But allow us to gather aggregated information about the use of our site. Businesspatrol.com pages may also contain web beacons inserted by our advertising agency so that we can measure the effectiveness of our advertising on other websites. Web beacon files enable our agency to recognise a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The web beacon only records a limited amount of information that includes the cookie number, the page id and the time and date the page was accessed, it does not contain your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address.   
[Find out more about web beacons](http://www.yell.com/legal/cookies/home.html#11). _How to manage the use of cookies on our website?_   
You can manage the cookies in the cookie folder of your browser. You can either delete cookies from your cookie folder once you have left our site, or you can set your preferences before you enter our website.   
Deleting or rejecting cookies may impair your experience of our website. You may not be able to access some pages or complete some transactions securely.   
[Find out more about deleting and rejecting cookies](http://www.yell.com/legal/cookies/home.html#10). 

**Disclosing information and consent**

 _Will Businesspatrol.com disclose information about me to other parties?_   
Not unless it's necessary for the operation of the site. We may also disclose personal information if it is legally required, or to enforce our conditions of use and other agreements, or to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Businesspatrol.com users or others. _Do you sell my details to other companies?_   
No, Businesspatrol.com does not sell user information to other companies. We may occasionally use the information we collect to send you details of offers or services that we think you might be interested in, but only if you've opted in during the registration process. These offers can be provided by a third party, but will always come from Businesspatrol.com. Each time we e-mail you, you can choose not to receive any further messages. _If I have given my consent, can I change my mind?_   
Yes, you can change your mind at any time by accessing your profile on Businesspatrol.com and changing your preferences. 

**Security**

 _Is my information secure?_   
Yes. We take the security of your personal data extremely seriously. We have implemented technology and security policies designed to protect the personal data under our control. We also follow strict security procedures as required by the UK Data Protection Act 1998. These cover the storage and disclosure of any information you've provided, and the prevention of unauthorised access. _Can anybody else who's using Businesspatrol.com access my personal details?_   
No. All personal information given to Businesspatrol.com is secured and stored away from public access. Credit card information is encrypted before any transaction takes place. _Is my information available to any companies who partner with Businesspatrol.com to provide products or services?_   
Yes, Businesspatrol.com may use partners to ensure the effective operation of our site. These companies have access to your personal information under our strict supervision and within the requirements of the Data Protection Act. 

**User access**

 _Can I access my personal information at any time?_   
Yes. If you want to look at or update your information, you can access all the details you provided us with when you registered. You can change or delete anything at any time.   
Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you're also entitled to view any information we hold on you by paying a fee. Details on how to do this are available from us or from the Office of the Information Commissioner. If any information held is inaccurate, we'll make the necessary changes and contact you with confirmation. _Can I correct or change any details I've given to you?_   
Yes. You can make changes to any of the information you gave us when you registered. Just access your profile and change your details as required. 

**Third party links**

Businesspatrol.com contains links to other sites. We cannot assume responsibility for any other site's content or information handling practices. We encourage you to review each site's privacy policy before entering into transactions with them.
